Guide to Congregation K'nesseth Israel [Baytown] Collection, 1931-2019 MS 924
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Congregation K'nesseth Israel [Baytown] Collection
1931-2019
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Linares, Joan
MS 924
2 Linear Feet 2 boxes
This collection consists of two boxes containing news clippings, newsletters, programs, photographs, scrapbooks, video tapes, and yearbooks documenting the history of Congregation K'nesseth Israel in Baytown, Texas, from 1931-2019.
Biographical / Historical
Chartered in 1928, Congregation K'nesseth Israel has served the Baytown Jewish community for over 90 years and enjoys a Texas Historical Marker. Although the building suffered damage following Hurricanes Ike and Harvey, the congregation and others in the Baytown community raised funds for its repair. K'nesseth Israel remains an important landmark in the South Texas Jewish community.
Content Description
Two boxes containing news clippings, newsletters, programs, photographs, scrapbooks, video tapes, and yearbooks document the history of Congregation K'nesseth Israel in Baytown, Texas, from 1931-2019.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection open for research. Stored off-site at the Library Service Center and requires 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Joan Linares, 2020.
Arrangement
The materials in this collection have been arranged in six series as follows: Series I: General; Series II: Hadassah; Series III: Articles and News Clippings; Series IV: Events; and Series V: Photographs / Scrapbooks; Series VI: Media
Separated Materials
An unpublished copy of "Oil Gevalt: The History of the Baytown, Texas, Jewish Community, 1928-2008 was cataloged separately and is available at the Woodson Research Center. Call Number: F395.J5 T46 2008
Index Terms
Subjects
Jews and Jewish life
Document Types
minutes (administrative records); newsletters; clippings (information artifacts); yearbooks; scrapbooks; videotapes; photographs
Subjects (Persons)
Linares, Joan
Subjects (Corporations)
Congregation K'nesseth Israel. (Houston, Tex)
- Series I: General
  - Meeting Minutes, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Former Members' Contact Information, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Torah Repair Information, 1993-1996 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Architect's Presentation on Synagogue Restoration, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Bylaws, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Programs, 1999-2014 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - TJHS Meeting Registration Form, 2019 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Exhibit (disassembled), n.d. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Historical Info, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Prayers, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Oversize exhibit
  - Pin-the-store-on-Texas-Avenue game
  - CKI Case Study Analysis conducted by UTSA
- Series II: Hadassah
  - Hadassah Yearbooks (1 of 6), 1956-1966 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Hadassah Yearbooks (2 of 6), 1967-1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Hadassah Meeting Minutes, 1971-1980 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Hadassah Yearbooks (3 of 6), 1983-1990 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Passover Recipes, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Hadassah Yearbooks (4 of 6), 1991-2001 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Hadassah Yearbooks (5 of 6), 2001-2011 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Hadassah Yearbooks (6 of 6), 2011-2017 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Series III: Articles & News Clippings
  - News Clippings — Misc., 1931-2018 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Articles — Misc., 1944-2018 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Baytown Jewish Community News (1 of 5), 1978-1979 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Baytown Jewish Community News (2 of 5), 1980-1989 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Baytown Jewish Community News (3 of 5), 1990-1999 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Baytown Jewish Community News (4 of 5), 2000-2009 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Baytown Jewish Community News (5 of 5), 2010-2015 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Series IV: Events
  - 50th Anniversary Materials, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Guestbook — Baytown Heritage Society Home Tour, 1989 (Box 2)
  - Historic Marker Materials, 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Guestbook — Historical Landmark Designation, 75th Anniversary, and Restoration Celebration, 1992-2011 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 75th Anniversary Materials, 2002-2004 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Door Replacement Materials, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Restoration Celebration Program, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - 90th Anniversary Celebration Materials, 2019 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - 90th Anniversary Celebration Kippah, 2019 (Box 1)
- Series V: Photographs / Scrapbooks
  - Photographs, 1991-1994 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook — Misc (1 of 2), 1991-1997 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook — Misc (2 of 2), 1998-2001 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 75th Anniversary Scrapbook, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Series VI: Media
  - 75th Anniversary VHS Tape, n.d. (Box 2)
  - Wings of Prayer Cassette Tape, n.d. (Box 2)